Guide to the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean records, 1959-1974.
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean records, 1959-1974
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine Office of the Dean records, 1959-1974.
24-1-1646
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine. Office of the Dean.
12 cubic ft.
Correspondence, minutes, financial and other records, date books, calendars, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes records of George C. Poppensiek as Dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes State University of New York correspondence, minutes of administrative staff, and other materials; records of the Cornell Faculty Senate; material on physical biology, 1957-1964; records of the Veterinary College Council; material on new Veterinary College buildings; budget requests and related records; date books and calendars; records of veterinarians' conferences; Association of American Veterinary Medicine Colleges material; American Veterinary Medical Association correspondence; traditional Christmas letters from the Dean to alumni, 1959-1973; and other records of George C. Poppensiek as Dean of the New York State College of Veterinary Medicine.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Veterinary Medicine. Office of the Dean.; Poppensiek, George C.; American Veterinary Medical Association.; Association of American Veterinary Colleges.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University. Faculty Senate.; New York State College of Veterinary Medicine--Administration.; State University of New York.
Subjects:
Veterinarians--United States.; Veterinary colleges--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- State University correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
- University Faculty, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
- Medicine and Obstetrics, 1958-1961 (Box 1)
- Medicine and Obstetrics, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Medicine and Obstetrics, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
- Physical and Radiation Biology Building, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Physical and Radiation Biology Building - Progress Report, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Physical and Radiation Biology Building - Plans, ca. 1962-1963 (Box 1)
- Physical Biology, 1963 (Box 1)
- Physical Biology, 1964 (Box 1)
- Pathology and Bacteriology, 1960-1962 (Box 1)
- Pathology and Bacteriology, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
- Virus Research Laboratory, 1959-1961 (Box 1)
- Virus Research Laboratory, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- Physical Biology, 1962 (Box 2)
- Physical Biology, 1961 (Box 2)
- Physical Biology, 1960 (Box 2)
- Physical Biology, 1959 (Box 2)
- Physical Biology, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
- New Veterinary College buildings; system of building and room designations (Box 2)
- Veterinary College (Box 2)
- Committee on names of new building (Box 2)
- Research at Veterinary College, 1962 (Box 2)
- Veterinary College Council, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
- Veterinary College Council, 1963 (Box 2)
- Veterinary College Council (Box 2)
- Council of NYS Veterinary College (Box 2)
- Sloan Award (Box 2)
- Letter sent to high school students - visiting Barton Hall (Box 2)
- Hagan portait fund (Box 2)
- Work-A-Day calendars, 1954-1956, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
- Five date books (Box 3)
- Ohio Board of Regents consultation, 1964 (Box 3)
- State University releases (Box 3)
- Faculty Senate (Box 3)
- 25th anniversary, State University of New York Convocation, Dec. 5, 1973 (Box 4)
- State forms, expense accts, travel orders, requisition of animals (Box 4)
- General committee report on rabies immunoprophylaxis (Box 4)
- Budget request - related material, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
- Budget request, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
- Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
- Budget, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
- Budget, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
- Veterinary Library private (Box 5)
- Libraries (Box 5)
- Administrative assistant Veterinary College (Box 5)
- Veterinary College Council, 1964 (Box 5)
- General Committee, 1958-1962 (Box 5)
- AID University College of East Africa Veterinary School - Kabete, Kenya (Box 5)
- Kenya, Veterinary College (Box 5)
- AID (Box 5)
- U.S. Department Health, Education and Welfare, U.S. Public Health, 1961- (Box 5)
- U.S. Public Health (Box 5)
- National Research Council (Box 5)
- State University (Box 5)
- Public Health 2nd Conference (Box 6)
- 52nd Annual Conference for Veterinarians, Jan. 6-8, 1960 (Box 6)
- Conference, 1959 (Box 6)
- Conference, 1958 (Box 6)
- Tuberculosis Eradication Conf., Sept. 6-7, 1961 (Box 6)
- The City of Ithaca, the Cornell Campus and the Proposed Laboratory Site, 1956 (Box 6)
- Mixed practice questionnaire (Box 6)
- Outline of Veterinary College courses (Box 6)
- Dogs (Box 6)
- Animal disease eradication (Box 6)
- NYS Dept. of Agr. and Markets (Box 6)
- NYS Education Department (Box 6)
- NYS Health Department (Box 6)
- NYS Harness Racing Commission (Box 6)
- NYS folders (Box 6)
- Tuition comparative data (Box 6)
- Tuition and fees (Box 6)
- Enrollment (State University) (Box 6)
- State University correspondence (Box 6)
- Herman Wells Committee to Study State University (Box 6)
- Faculty Senate (Box 6)
- Audit and Control report: NYS field audit, 1969-1971 (Box 7)
- Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
- Borden Company (Box 7)
- Walls Report (Box 7)
- AAVMC President, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
- Forms (Box 7)
- Financial AAVMC (Box 7)
- Inauguration Chancellor Ernest L. Boyer, Apr. 6, 1971 (Box 7)
- South American trip (Box 8)
- Food Science and Technology (Box 8)
- Budget hearings, departmental, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
- Association of American Veterinary Medicine Colleges, 1971 (Box 8)
- Association of American Veterinary Medicine Colleges, 1970 (Box 8)
- Association of American Veterinary Medicine Colleges, 1967-1969 (Box 8)
- American Veterinary Medical Association correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 8)
- AVMA Executive Vice President (Box 8)
- Veterinary Medicine Review Committee, BHME-NIH-site visit (Box 9)
- Alan J. Grout, Assistant to the Dean (Box 9)
- Maria Spinelli (Box 9)
- Subcommittee on Introduction on Foreign Pathogens (Box 9)
- Committee on Animal Health NAS-NRC, 1969 (Box 9)
- Symposium on Animal Disease Reporting, May 1969 (Box 9)
- Subcommittee on Morbidity and Mortality Committee on Animal Health (Box 9)
- Manuscript morbidity and mortality reporting (Box 9)
- 62nd Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 61st Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 60th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 59th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 58th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 57th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 56th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 55th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 54th Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- 53rd Annual Conference for Veterinarians (Box 10)
- Mr. S.C. Kent, 1970-1972 (Box 10)
- Multicategorical Research Wing, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
- B&P building maintenance (Box 10)
- Laboratory Animal Research Facility (Box 10)
- Multicategorical Research Wing (Box 10)
- Diagnostic Laboratories (discussions), 1969 (Box 10)
- Diagnostic Laboratory (Box 10)
- Department budget hearings, FY 1971-1972 (Box 11)
- Cornell Provost and Vice Provost, 1968-1970 (Box 11)
- President's retreat, 1966 (Box 11)
- Cornell faculty, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
- Campus issues, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
- Cornell Deans' Council meetings, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
- State University of N.Y., 1969-1970 (Box 11)
- Laboratory Animal Resource Committee Upstate Medical Center, State Univ. of N.Y. (Box 11)
- State University of New York units heads meeting, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
- National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges, Minneapolis, Minnesota 79th Annual Convention, Nov. 1965 (Box 11)
- Correspondence relative to nominations for successors of two retiring dept. heads (Box 11)
- Department budget hearings, FY 1974-1975 (Box 11)
- University Committee on Campus Planning (Box 12)
- Tuskegee Institute, 1971 (Box 12)
- Trustee Visiting Comm. Tuskegee Institute, 1970 (Box 12)
- Tuskegee Institute, 1969 (Box 12)
- National Advisory Food and Drug Council, FDA (Box 12)
- National Advisory Food and Drug Council minutes, 1968 (Box 12)
- Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, Brazil, 1969 (Box 12)
- Escola de Veterinaria Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais, Brazil (Box 12)
- Colombia (Box 12)
- Ford Foundation, miscellaneous correspondence (Box 12)
- Veterinary Science, San Marcos University, Lima, Peru (Box 12)
- University of the South Argentina (Ford Foundation), 1965 (Box 12)
- Christmas letters (1 vol. was original collection), 1959-1973 (Box 12)
  See Call number SF756.35.C67 C4, also other issues are available in collection #24-4-3390 and available online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/45066